MADELEINE GUETTLER

Professional Summary

A dedicated and determined individual with strong communication and teamwork skills. My goal in life is to give back to the world through social work and data science majors. Highly organized, hardworking, perfectionistic, and driven.

Accomplishments

- Honor Roll in High School
- Several 1st place awards in Martial Arts tournaments
- Assistant Concertmaster/Principle throughout seven years at Boston Youth Symphony Orchestras

Work History

Simmons University - Research Assistant

Boston, MA

Spring 2022 – Current

- Assist Computational linguistics professor at Simmons in her NSF funded prosody research.
- Team up with students across several universities to clean up and manipulate data. In addition to setting up experiments focusing on prosody-based hypotheses for participants to take part in.
- Currently exploring different machine algorithms such as random forest and kmeans to find optimal algorithm for incoming data.

Johnny Burke's Catering-Server

Boston MA

Summer 2022 - Current

- Work throughout Boston area as a server, lead server, or manager depending on event
- Actively work as large team with clear communication and trust in order to create not only the most professional and smooth service possible, but to create lasting positive memories in clients' lives.

Simmons University - Teacher Assistant

Boston, MA

Fall 2022 - Current

- Engaged in helping students understand statistic concepts in Intro to Stats in addition to learning how to code in R
- Meet bi-weekly with other teacher assistants and course professors to discuss areas that teacher assistants could help support students in based off of previous semesters.

Hope Gain Center of West Michigan - New Program Committee Member

Grand Rapids, MI

March 2021 - April 2022

- Created support programs for individuals struggling with mental health.
- Give seminars, do research, and help in fundamental key steps necessary to create up and running programs.

MGH Center for Systems Biology Research Informatics Core – Web Intern Boston, MA

Spring 2019 - Spring 2021

- Helped design/create websites for organizations within Massachusetts General Brigham and outside clients meant to help with better data management.
- Developed key communication, teamwork, and time management skills through consistently working closely with clients and colleagues.

Cambridge Health Alliance - Shadow Intern

Cambridge, MA

April 2018 – June 2018

Worked to deepen my understanding of the psycho-bio-social sphere/model and observed this model in play through the shadowing of staff members.

guettler@simmons.edu

617-888-5046



Newton, MA, 02459

Skills

- Microsoft, Google Docs, PowerPoint, Excel
- Python
- R Programming
- MongoDB, MySQL

Education

Expected in December 2024

Simmons University

Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science: Data

Science

Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework:

STAT 118 – Intro to Statistics STAT 227 – Intermediate

Statistics: Design & Analysis

STAT 228 – Introduction to

Data Science

CS 112 – Intro to Computer Science

CS 221 – Database Management

CS 346 – Data Mining

BIO 113 – General Biology

Expected in December 2024

Simmons University

Boston, MA

Minor in Social Work

Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Relevant Coursework:

SW 255 –Interviewing & Doc in Human Service

SW 253 – Human Behavior in

Social Environment

SW 200 – Social Welfare Policy

June 2018

Newton South High School

Newton, MA

High School Diploma

Languages

- English
- German